JADE ABBOTT-MICKELSON

UX/UI, Web Design

www.jadeofalltrades.github.io/

Design Skills

Research

Surveys, Interviews, Persona building, Sketching, Wireframing

Front-End:

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

Design Tools

Figma, InVision, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Sketch

Projects

Honeycomb Cloud Storage

https://invis.io/T8UUJLSP9YE

Cloud storage solution with an emphasis on saving and organization.

User research indicated that organization was the greatest frustration with other storage solutions. I solved this using a Pinterest-style approach, where content is organized first.

Contact

E-mail

jmickelsondesigns@gmail.com

Cell

916-261-8169

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/jade-mickelson

Education

Biological Sciences

Sacramento City College

Design Experience

Bloc Product Design

May 2019-March 2020

Learned industry best practices and design standards focusing on UX Research, Visual Design, and Front-End development. Created and deployed projects while learning new tools and frameworks by collaborating weekly with a senior product designer.

Lead Designer, The Witching Hour Collective

May 2019-Present

Worked closely with the client to develop branding assets for a local candle company. This included consulting, marketing materials, and website development.

Front Desk Lead, Byuti Salon & Spa, Tru DOCO

January 2019-Present

Designed flyers, invitations, templates, and layouts for marketing materials. Consulted owner on design choices and projects, and assisted in design choices for a new salon website.

Other Experience

General Manager, My Friend William Inc.

April 2016-August 2018

Designed flyers and invitations for print. Worked closely with ownership to manage a busy downtown specialty coffeehouse and a staff ranging from four to eight high skill individuals. Oversaw training at all levels and promoted high quality beverage craft.

Volunteer, Sac DESCO

November 2019-Present

Collaborate with local multidisciplinary design collective to host workshops and events, designed marketing materials, and provide support to emerging designers.